hey everyone welcome to another lesson
in this task automation course
today i'm going to talk about what's the
new way of setting up tosca on your
machine
now this i have already
done in another previous session
but
tosca has now changed the way
you can download the software and
install it right so previously you had
to create a account on the support
portal and then you could download
that particular tool and then you also
had to apply
for a license
a trial license right but now they have
made it more simpler right so let's see
what are the new steps to set up tosca
on your machine
so obviously first you need to go to the
trycenters.com
website right there uh just go to demos
and trials
and here you will find uh there are
number of
uh different tools
provided by trust centers
and there you'll find tracentis.com
right
so click on free trial
and that will take you to this page
right where you can request for a trial
license for trying this task
now before that uh you should check what
are the system requirements for
downloading tosca right
so
you should have some uh 1.4 gb space uh
it will take five to ten minutes
to download
um and a stable internet connection and
windows 7 and above right
so these are all the different system
requirements
now if you want to see um how long this
is uh you
can actually extend it by 30 days but
beyond that you need to contact them
now
it doesn't uh activate other products uh
like the new load or
queue test by class centers it is just
made for tosca
okay
so um these are some faqs which you can
go through on this particular page now
we need to request a particular license
a trial license for
tosca
so you need to put
email address
i will put my email address
okay
and
put all the details which are
required here
put your company name
and put some role of what you are
interested in
so
what kind of testing you want to do
although it's optional you can leave it
empty goals for this trial so you want
to learn
tosca
okay and
you can check these options and then you
can click on submit
okay so now um it will tell you what
happens next right it will also show you
a video of how to install class and this
tasker
right
then you can activate your license there
is another video and you can create your
first test case right
so everything is present here
you can follow the steps here
and here
you can
click on it to start the file download
which is around 1.4 gb
and it's that oscar 15 lts version
so once the download is complete go to
the downloads folder and double click on
the transcendence tosca installer
that should launch the setup page
now
because i already have a tosca version
which is lower than this version 14.3 so
it is giving me an option to upgrade to
the latest version which i have
downloaded
but uh if you are installing it for the
first time it will just take you through
the setup you just need to follow the
instructions given on the screen and
complete the installation
so once the installation is complete so
let me close the screen
so once the installation is complete and
you are able to launch presenters tosca
go to project and under that you will
see the license section
so in this license section
if you have got a license you should see
a screen like this
everything is fine you got license
if not
click on this connect right
and that will give you an option to
connect to an existing license server
now after that you need to select on
connect to cloud hosted license server
and click on ok
ok so here you need to enter the
username and password but this user
should be the same username which or the
email address which you used while
requesting a trial license
and you need to also make sure that you
need to use the same email address when
you are creating a account on the
transcendence portal right so enter that
email uh which will be the username and
then the password which you had given
while creating your tricenters portal uh
user
now before continuing further as i said
you need to have also an account on the
transcendence portal right so this is
the support hub centers dot com here you
need to register yourself
and you need to give a business email
right so this email should be the same
one which you provided while requesting
for a try license and then
downloading the file okay
so once you register yourself right um
on the stash in this portal and you are
able to login with the email and
password
the same username and password uh could
be provided on the transcendence tasker
while activating your license
now coming back to tosca once you have
given the username and password it will
give you this message uh by connecting
to the cloud license
that you have successfully connected to
the license server right
and then you can launch your tusk
commander
with the activated license